<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Programming | Zerillian Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-24T02:23:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Armand Zerilli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming From Above]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/03/28/programming-from-above/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T02:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/03/28/programming-from-above</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Language Extensions, Preprocessors, and Abstractions</h2>

<p>Programming is a pain in the ass more often than I'd like to admit to the people that make fun of my job. Thanks to programmers better at this than I am, there's a practical smorgasbord of pain-relieving utilities. The regular web languages weren't exactly built for making us happy, but a lot of people still take them unsweetened.</p>

<p>For the most part, I'm the straight-edge type. So what if I instead went cold turkey on the straight-edge languages and wrapped 'em up in something prettier? Well, with great optimism and the echoes of <em>"why not?"</em> on my brain...</p>

<h3>LET'S FIND OUT.</h3>

<!-- more -->


<p>HTML has to be the first on the chopping block. Fleshed-out HTML, the likes of which you'll find in almost every tutorial, guide, and textbook, contains a lot more information than what's really necessary to produce fine results. And perfectly valid results at that. In fact, you might surprised at <a href="http://openmymind.net/Minimalist-Markup/">how some people compact HTML</a> and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=677125">how much you can omit without issue.</a></p>

<p>I really figured out how repetitive HTML can be while I worked without an IDE or code editor; essentially without code completion. So I'd like to make a distinction here: Auto-completion alone does not a simple language make. HTML is just as bitter as ever. It'll be the likes of HAML that truly improve the writing experience.</p>

<p>So here's resolution number one:</p>

<h3>ARMAND, DON'T YOU DARE WRITE ANOTHER LINE OF STANDARD HTML.</h3>

<p>Sounds weird. The cold turkey aspect may be harder with this one, but it should be noted that HTML isn't really the language I'm most radically sweetening. It may help with tools like <a href="http://emmet.io">Emmet (http://emmet.io)</a> by my side to grease my fingners with lightning. However, Emmet is still an editing tool, it doesn't improve HTML as a language. It just makes writing it easier.</p>

<p>One of these core languages is <em>definitely</em> getting supercharged. CSS. This brings us to resolution number two:</p>

<h3>USE A CSS PREPROCESSOR ALWAYS. IF YOU WRITE ANYTHING WITHOUT MIXINS, I'LL EAT YOU ALIVE.</h3>

<p>CSS feels like one of those languages that should mostly be handled by machines. Clarification: If we want to write stylesheets expressively, we should leave the raw CSS to machines.</p>

<p>Sass has become my preferred stylesheet language, and I plan on using it in this transition period. If I stay with regular CSS, powerful enhancements to the CSS editor's workflow will just pass me by.</p>

<p>Though I have to say that Sass even seems a little much at times. Stylus squirrels away the normal machine readability. We humans know how to structure without braces, brackets, and (semi)colons. I need a language capable of understanding that.</p>

<p>And finally, resolving some discomforts with what is my least favorite web language...</p>

<h3>COFFEESCRIPT. GET WITH THE PROGRAM. SHOOT IT INTO YOUR VEINS IF YOU HAVE TO.</h3>

<p>I'm serious, I don't like JavaScript. It's just odd. CoffeeScript helps. Learning and applying it will make my code cleaner and more maintainable. I mean, <a href="http://coffeescript.org">look at their website.</a> Most of the CoffeeScript examples are less than half of the length of the JavaScript they cross-compile to.</p>

<p>There's also an interesting by-product to this transition. If I'm working with preprocessors and extensions and whatnot, most of them need compiling and distributing. I recently got my hands on software that'll automatically compile these things, which means my projects and frameworks are now separated. It's encouraging me to not only work at a higher level but organize my projects more freely and distinctly. I put source files where they make the most sense to me.</p>

<p>It'll be tough. But I believe it will also reward me with deeper understanding of these marvelous new tools. For too long I've been addicted to brackets, braces, semicolons, prefixes, all these ugly characters... I'll have some withdrawal. I'll be tempted to cave...</p>

<p>BUT NO. IT'S GO TIME.</p>

<p>Also, as a final commentary on editing blog posts, restraint is a good thing. This post used to be about twice as long.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
