<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Laravel | Zerillian Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/categories/laravel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-24T02:23:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Armand Zerilli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supercharged Testing With the IoC Container]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/04/17/supercharged-ioc-testing/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-17T13:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/04/17/supercharged-ioc-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Laravel provides a great implementation of an IoC container, which has a wonderful smorgasbord of uses. One particularly useful case is customized experimental texting when building your application.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>SO WHAT THE HELL IS AN IoC CONTAINER?</h3>

<p>You can skip this if you're savvy, but some people jumping into PHP and Laravel for the first time might not grasp this yet.</p>

<p>IoC stands for <em>Inversion of Control.</em>  When you typically write software modules, they're well defined from the get-go and glued into their frames of functionality. Your code is on a canvas, and once you paint it, you'll have to paint over it to change anything.</p>

<p>IoC containers are more like sticky notes. Sticky notes come in the hundreds, and they're all the same. You peel off a sticky note when you need one and write specifically what you need on it. Every note is identical, but you've added special information at the point at which you need it. It serves as your reminder for as long as you require, then you crumple it up and try to toss it in a trash bin that's too far away.</p>

<p>An IoC container turns your code into sticky notes. You stick your daily reminders on  there along with the regular items that you need to do. Like a reminder to buy more Jarlsberg. Nobody is going to break out the brushes to paint cheese on their canvases. You peel off a sticky note, write BUY CHEESE on it, and put it where it's visible.</p>

<h2>Make Your Modules Into Sticky Notes</h2>

<p>Inverting Control means defining objects at runtime, as your code is being evaluated. It encourages a very high level of decoupling the reusable code from the problem-specific code because you're creating modules on the spot that solve specific problems by extending reusable modules as needed.</p>

<p>How about this:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
