<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Anecdotes | Zerillian Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/categories/anecdotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-23T02:32:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Armand Zerilli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[50 Cents Doesn't Buy a Lot of Trouble]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/07/10/50-cents-doesnt-buy-a-lot-of-trouble/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-10T22:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/07/10/50-cents-doesnt-buy-a-lot-of-trouble</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here in Ithaca, we've got a pleasant little outdoor concourse of restaurants and merchant establishments running beside pavilions and statues and trees: The Ithaca Commons. Lately, it's had everything ripped out for rennovation, but... Still.</p>

<p>Whenever I'm on the Commons, I go to a toy store on State street and buy a bouncy ball for 50 cents. As I walk, I bounce it on the ground and against walls. It's a benign, calming activity. I've thrown them against buildings, bounced them high in the air, and naturally lost all of them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I've accidentally flung them out into the streets, at windows, down drains, and even into other people. I keep buying them and losing them every time. I don't mind. It adds an element of chaos to a life I spend so much time structuring. Those superballs are utterly unpredictable.</p>

<p>For a while, I can control them. Though it's inevitable that they hit a pebble and bounce far off, leading me into a stumbling chase to recapture them. It keeps happening, and I never know when. All I can do is run clumsily and make attempts at snatching them, thinking the whole time that there's a good chance I never see that ball again.</p>

<p>Chaos is necessary. It shatters my perception that I have anything more than a suggestive input on my life. In reality, I control very little. Somehow the universe keeps working fairly predictably, but it's easy to forget that I can lose control in an instant to a roll of the metaphoric dice.</p>

<p>So those little bouncy rubber balls serve not only as a fun distraction, but a reminder that the gears of these ephemeral probability engines are always grinding; they are constantly on the verge of engaging with potentially life-changing force. Part of me hopes that when I lose one of those balls it rolls into another life and adds some intrigue. They forcibly put predictability on hold and seed chaotic activity.</p>

<p>In a time when fifty cents doesn't buy a whole lot of trouble, I consider that a triumph.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
