<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Writing | Zerillian Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-29T00:21:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Armand Zerilli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excess Verbosity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/04/08/excess-verbosity/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T15:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/04/08/excess-verbosity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a tendency toward verbosity. I'm a really wordy person. TOO WORDY, IN FACT.</p>

<p>I think the reason I do it stems from a fear that my ideas won't get through to people. I used to have to explain things to non-technical people, and sometimes that made my brain go around in circles attempting to come up with the right words. I got rather accustomed to stringing words together that had to adjust previous words with more detail, supposedly assuring that I wasn't misunderstood. By the way, there's one word for that paragraph: <em>Pleonasm.</em></p>

<p>Mostly it just confused people, so something had to give.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I wrote some emails recently, and boy were they motormouthed, perhaps <em>incongruously</em> so. I mean, I've got a little OS X launcher utility that can do thesaurus lookups. It's been getting more use lately.</p>

<p>I also have friends that like to edit their writing only as they write it. Those works tend to be quite <em>tautological.</em> The fault is a lack of a unifying <em>cynosure</em>. My emails tend to be like that, unfortunately. Conversational tones give a <em>congenial</em> feel to these communications, but I think I've overdone it.</p>

<p>See? A little refined vocabulary cuts away superfluity. I've learned to work that thesaurus and boil down sentences to core meaning, finding out if I've repeated things too often. It's a rule now.</p>

<p>For others with <em>circuitous</em> writing issues, it's a good idea to keep a dictionary app open all the time. Or, if you're the type that's very grounded in the tangible world, a pocket thesaurus. If you're a Mac user, you've already got Dictionary.app and built-in word lookups basically everywhere.</p>

<p>This whole <em>less is more</em> thing works in surprising places. And remember that people love to work with strong writers. Make the most of your paragraphs.</p>

<p>That, and when you use sophisticated vocabulary, you're giving the reader an opportunity for a nice little educational experience. Who doesn't like learning new words?</p>

<p>Everybody wins.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
