<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Business | Zerillian Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/categories/business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-30T05:42:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Armand Zerilli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cry Me a River, Emails]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/03/26/cry-me-a-river-emails/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.zerilliworks.net/blog/2013/03/26/cry-me-a-river-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Or: Why You Should NEVER Make Robots Fake Sincerity</h3>

<p>While helping a friend construct a website, I signed up for Weebly. I didn't even have a website, I was just a collaborator. I didn't want anything to do with Weebly. For some reason, she began getting uncomfortably clingy. Look at this as an example of how to creep out your customers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I'll be clear now that I do not like drag-and-drop site builders. Only one such service have I ever described in terms that may be optimistically construed as "fond" -- that service being Squarespace. And that's only because they opened up their internals to developers.</p>

<p>So have a look at this.</p>

<p><img src="/images/articles/Weebly-Believing.png" title="Don't stop believin' (in your website)" ></p>

<p><a href="/extras/weebly-believing.html">If you can't see the image, click here for the text version.</a></p>

<p>The time since I signed up is probably the second worst thing about this. It's just odd. It reminds me that there is some task somewhere (clearly not a human) that is looking over less-than-frequently-active accounts and telling them to get going. It's unbelievably insincere, and it's frankly a little condescending. How so?</p>

<blockquote><p>Maybe you got busy and forgot about your website. We understand. When you signed up you probably had a vision for your site. We want to help you make that a reality. We promise that Weebly truly is the easiest way to create a website.</p></blockquote>

<p>Of course I had a vision. Perhaps I own a business, I sell goods, I'm an artist, I'm a traveller, I'm a game show contestant with a penchant for blogging. What's gonna matter is my content. If I'm passionate enough, I'll find the best way to present it. I am disinclined to believe that anyone who has any real desire to run a website would forget about it for 29 days, 16 hours, 7 minutes and 47 seconds.</p>

<p>This helpful message is a little too chummy. It is certainly not sincerely endorsed by the Weebly Team, it was sent by a robot that's been told how to sound friendly. A person wrote generic text without much thought and I was on the receiving end of a template engine fed with those words. Nothing really makes me feel less cared for than robots acting like people. Giving them a little personality can be okay, but this is kind of insulting. Is your team actually nervous that I might not realize the full potential of my business? That's something investors worry about. And something robots think nothing of.</p>

<p>Then this happens:</p>

<p><img src="/images/articles/Weebly-Sniffle.png" title="Sniffle. Sniffle..." ></p>

<p><a href="/extras/weebly-sniffle.html">If you can't see the image, click here for the text version.</a></p>

<p>The subject of this message was literally "That's sad." No, this email is the sad thing. You trained machines to sound sympathetic, and it's just unsettling to make them cry. <em>For the love of God, knock it off.</em> There's nothing wrong with the concept of automated messages. But <em>please</em> do not make them f--king cry. That does not make me feel cared for. Your team doesn't seem to be there for me, it seems like you need to clutch your flaky customers in a death grip.</p>

<p>Don't fret though, you fantastically sincere liars, I think this email could be fixed pretty easily.</p>

<p><img src="/images/articles/Weebly-Sniffle-fixed.png" title="Just take a Sharpie to it." ></p>

<p>There. That's basically free advice, Weebly. If your team is feeling sincere and nervous and sympathetic, my typical consulting fee is $17,000.</p>

<p>For the record, one of their founders eventually sent me a personal email asking for feedback. Way to go, fellas. That's where you lay on the charm, in the actual exchanges between actual people. That redeemed their support team a bit. That was someone who was really wondering what went wrong and wanted to find a solution. I'm not being sarcastic there, if you're looking to connect with a customer, a real live human being is the way to do it. I absolutely love that.</p>

<p>Sending automated emails that cry is tantamount to deception. That's what I have to say to them.</p>

<p>I can't be the only person that feels this way. I very highly value genuine interactions, and pretty much any attempt to imbue emotion without real effort is simply insulting to me.</p>

<p>Seriously, without the mendacious nervousness and sniffles, these would be just helpful emails. I might have read them without rolling my eyes.</p>

<p>If you're someone who also dislikes this sort of indiscretion, I'd appreciate a comment so I know I'm not alone.</p>

<p>Also, if you happen to be an English professor and would like to tell me whether I should have used <em>whom</em> in that last sentence, I would appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
